Register of the Socialist Workers Party records
Hoover Institution Archives
- BARNES/WATERS FILE, 1964-1990
  - 1982
    - United Secretariat meeting, March 11-14 (Folder 13)
    - United Secretariat meeting, May 21-22 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - International Executive Committee plenum, May 22-30
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Minutes (Folder 3)
      - Notes (Folder 4)
      - Central America and Caribbean discussions. Reports and declaration (Folder 5)
      - Industrial Turn discussions. Report, questionnaire and memoranda (Folder 6)
      - Iran discussions. Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 7)
      - Israel discussions. Draft resolution and discussion documents (Folder 8)
      - Malvinas War discussions. Draft declarations (Folder 9)
      - Militarism discussions. Draft resolution and discussion documents (Folder 10)
      - Sri Lanka discussions. Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 11)
      - United States discussions (re Socialist Workers Party). Statements and discussion documents (Folder 12)
      - Other discussions. Reports, draft resolutions, and discussion documents (Folder 13)
    - United Secretariat meeting, May 30 (Folder 14)
    - United Secretariat meeting, September 2-3 (Folder 15)
    - United Secretariat meeting, October 6-10 (Folder 16)
  - 1983
    - United Secretariat meeting, January 24-27 (Folder 17)
    - United Secretariat meeting, March 12-14 (Folder 18)
    - United Secretariat meeting, May 27-30
      - General (Folder 19)
      - Building the International report. Draft (Folder 20)
      - World Situation report. Draft (Folder 21)
    - United Secretariat meeting, September 7-8 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - United Secretariat meeting, October 20-24
      - General (Folder 2)
      - United States discussions (re Socialist Workers Party). Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 3)
  - 1984
    - United Secretariat meeting, January 26-29 (Folder 4)
    - European Political Bureaus meeting, February-March (Folder 5)
    - United Secretariat meeting, May 10-14
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Socialist Workers Party motions and countermotions (Folder 7)
      - East discussions (re Soviet Union, Eastern Europe, China). Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 8)
      - Great Britain discussions. Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 9)
      - United States Elections discussions. Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 10)
      - United States Splits (of Fourth Internationalist Tendency and Socialist Action from Socialist Workers Party) discussions. Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 11)
    - United Secretariat meeting, September 6-9 (Folder 12)
    - Latin American Political Bureaus meeting, September (Folder 13)
    - United Secretariat meeting, November 8-11 (Box 69)
      - General (Folder 1-2)
      - Cuba discussions. Draft amendments (Folder 3)
      - Sri Lanka discussions. Report (Folder 4)
  - 1985
    - International Executive Committee plenum, January 26-27
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Brazil discussions. Background printed articles (Folder 6)
    - World Congress Faction meeting, January 31 (Folder 7)
    - World Congress (12th), January-February
      - Pre-Congress preparatory reports (Folder 8)
      - Appeal to the delegates (by certain members of the International Executive Committee) (Folder 9)
      - Appeals Commissions proceedings (Folder 10)
      - Notes (Folder 11)
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Poland discussions. Draft amendments and discussion document (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Evaluations (Folder 2)
    - United Secretariat meeting, April 23-27
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Notes (Folder 4)
      - Bolivia discussions. Background material (Folder 5)
      - Great Britain discussions. Background material (Folder 6)
      - Yugoslavia discussions. Background material (Folder 7)
    - United Secretariat meeting, June 17-21
      - Minutes (Folder 8)
      - Notes (Folder 9)
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Great Britain discussions. Background material (Folder 11)
      - United States discussions (re Socialist Workers Party and rivals). Background material (including Socialist Action internal bulletins and other circulated internal documents) (Folder 12-13)
    - Latin American Political Bureaus meeting, September (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - United Secretariat meeting, September 30-October 5
      - Notes (Folder 2)
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Australia discussions. Preparatory material (Folder 4)
      - South Africa discussions. Draft resolutions and preparatory material (Folder 5)
      - United States discussions (re Socialist Workers Party and rivals). Draft declarations and preparatory material (Folder 6)
    - European Political Bureaus meeting, November 16-22 (Folder 7)
    - United Secretariat meeting, December 16-20
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Great Britain discussions. Draft resolution, report, and preparatory material
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Socialist League national conference documents (Folder 10)
  - 1986
    - International Executive Committee plenum, February 23-March 2
      - Notes (Folder 11)
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Great Britain discussions. Draft resolutions and preparatory material (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Indochina discussions. Reports (Folder 2)
      - Iran discussions. Draft resolutions and preparatory material (Folder 3)
      - Nicaragua discussions. Reports (Folder 4)
      - South Africa discussions. Draft resolutions (Folder 5)
      - United States discussions (re Socialist Workers Party and rivals). Reports and draft resolutions and statements (Folder 6)
      - Background material
        - General (Folder 7)
        - United States (Socialist Action and Fourth Internationalist Tendency circulated internal documents) (Folder 8)
    - United Secretariat meeting, April 29-30 (Folder 9)
    - United Secretariat meeting, June 9-13
      - General (Folder 10)
      - France. Background material (Lutte Ouvrière circulated internal documents) (Folder 11)
    - Latin American International Executive Committee meeting, September 17 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - United Secretariat meeting, September 29-October 1 (Folder 2)
    - European Political Bureaus meeting, October 28-November 1 (Folder 3)
    - United Secretariat meeting, December 16-19 (Folder 4)
  - 1987
    - United Secretariat meeting, March 2-6 (Folder 5)
    - International Executive Committee plenum, June 19-29
      - Notes (Folder 6)
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Philippines discussions. Draft resolutions and background material (Folder 8)
      - Soviet Union discussions. Statement, discussion document, and background material (Folder 9)
      - Women's Commission discussions. Draft resolutions and discussion documents (Folder 10)
    - United Secretariat meeting, November 2-6 (Folder 11)
  - 1988
    - United Secretariat meeting, March
      - Notes (Folder 12)
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Great Britain discussions. Draft resolutions and preparatory material (Folder 14)
    - International Executive Committee plenum, December 3-9 (Box 74)
      - Notes (Folder 1)
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Great Britain discussions. Draft resolutions (Folder 3)
      - Soviet Union discussions. Report and draft resolutions (Folder 4)
      - United States discussions (re Socialist Workers Party and rivals). Draft resolutions and preparatory material (Folder 5)
      - Women's Commission discussions. Reports, draft resolutions, discussion documents, and preparatory material (Folder 6)
  - 1990
    - General (Folder 7)
    - United Secretariat meeting, February 24-March 2 (Folder 8)
    - International Executive Committee plenum, June 4-10 (Folder 9)
- LENINIST-TROTSKYIST FACTION FILE, 1973-1977
  Records of the Socialist Workers Party's interactions with the Leninist-Trotskyist Faction, an international faction within the Fourth International, including correspondence, minutes, reports, and discussion documents. Consists mainly of sets of circulated internal documents.
  - General (Box 51)
    - Europe position paper. Draft, 1976 (Folder 7)
    - Steering Committee membership, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - Chronological file
    - 1973
      - August (Folder 9)
      - September (Folder 10)
      - October (Folder 11)
      - November (Folder 12)
      - December (Folder 13)
    - 1974
      - January (Folder 14)
      - March (Folder 15)
      - April (Folder 16)
      - May (Folder 17)
      - June (Folder 18)
      - July (Folder 19)
      - August (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - September (Folder 2)
      - October (Folder 3)
      - November (Folder 4)
      - December (Folder 5)
    - 1975
      - January (Folder 6)
      - February (Folder 7)
      - March (Folder 8)
      - April (Folder 9)
      - May (Folder 10)
      - June (Folder 11)
      - July (Folder 12)
      - August (Folder 13)
      - September (Folder 14)
      - October (Folder 15)
      - November (Folder 16)
      - December (Folder 17)
    - 1976 (Box 53)
      - January (Folder 1)
      - February (Folder 2)
      - March (Folder 3)
      - April (Folder 4)
      - May (Folder 5)
      - June (Folder 6)
      - July (Folder 7)
      - August (Folder 8)
      - September (Folder 9)
      - October (Folder 10)
      - December (Folder 11)
    - 1977 (Box 74)
      - January (Folder 10)
      - March (Folder 11)
      - May (Folder 12)
      - June (Folder 13)
      - July (Folder 14)
      - August (Folder 15)
      - September (Folder 16)
  - Geographical file (Box 53)
    - Argentina, 1976 (Folder 12)
    - Belgium, 1974-1976 (Folder 13)
    - Canada, 1974 (Folder 14)
    - Costa Rica, 1976 (Folder 15)
    - Denmark, 1970-1975 (Folder 16)
    - France, 1973-1975 (Folder 17)
    - Germany, 1973-1975 (Folder 18)
    - Great Britain, 1973-1976 (Folder 19)
    - Hong Kong, 1975-1976 (Folder 20)
    - Ireland, 1974 (Folder 21)
    - Mexico, 1974-1975 (Folder 22)
    - Portugal, 1976 (Folder 23)
    - Spain, 1973 (Folder 24)
    - Sweden, 1973 (Folder 25)
    - United States, 1974-1976 (Folder 26)
- ARCHIVAL SOURCES.
  Reports and lists of material on the history of the Fourth International at Harvard University, the Internationaal Institut voor Sociale Geschiedenis, the Bibliothèque de Documentation Internationale Contemporaine and elsewhere
  - Archival sources. (Box 74, Folder 27)
- GELFAND VS. SMITH ET AL. FILE, 1979-1990
  Legal records and background material, relating to the legal case of Gelfand vs. Smith et al., in which Socialist Workers Party leaders were defendants, including trial and hearing transcripts, exhibits, depositions, legal motions and briefs, correspondence, internal reports, and printed matter.
  - Trial transcript, 1983 (Box 75)
    - March 2 (Folder 1)
    - March 3 (Folder 2)
    - March 4 (Folder 3)
    - March 8 (Folder 4)
    - March 9 (Folder 5)
  - Trial exhibits, 1983
    - No. 1-13 (Folder 6)
    - No. 14-20 (Folder 7)
    - No. 31-46 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - No. 47 (Folder 2)
    - No. 48-83 (Folder 3)
    - No. 84-102 (Folder 4)
    - No. 103 (Folder 5)
    - No. 104 (Folder 6)
    - No. 105-106 (Folder 7)
    - No. 107-108 (Folder 8)
    - No. 109-110 (Folder 9)
    - No. 111-112 (Folder 10)
    - No. 113 (Folder 11)
    - No. 114 (Folder 12)
    - No. 115 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - No. 116-118 (Folder 2)
    - No. 119 (Folder 3)
    - No. 120-140 (Folder 4)
    - No. 141-160 (Folder 5)
    - No. 161-180 (Folder 6)
    - No. 181-183, unnumbered (Folder 7)
    - Objections. Key to objections to exhibits (Folder 8)
  - Deposition transcripts, 1980-1983
    - General. Lists and miscellany (Folder 9)
    - Notices of depositions by plaintiff, 1980-1983
      - B-L (Folder 10)
      - M-Z (Folder 11)
    - Notices of depositions by Socialist Workers Party defendants, 1982-1983 (Folder 12)
    - Barnes, Jack, 1982 (Box 78)
      - March 6 (Folder 1)
      - March 7 (Folder 2)
      - March 8 (Folder 3)
      - March 9 (Folder 4)
      - (as custodian of records), March 9 (Folder 5)
      - Exhibits to depositions (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Indexes to deposition testimony (Folder 2)
    - Britton, Joel, 1982 April 21 (Folder 3)
    - Camejo, Peter, 1982
      - March 11 (Folder 4)
      - March 12 (Folder 5)
    - Chertov, Pearl, 1982 April 13 (Folder 6)
    - Dobbs, Farrell, 1982 (Box 80)
      - April 10 (Folder 1)
      - April 11 (Folder 2)
      - April 12 (Folder 3)
    - Doxsee, Sylvia [Sylvia Franklin; Sylvia Caldwell]
      - 1980 September 22 (Folder 4)
      - Exhibits to deposition (Folder 5)
    - Fisher, Barry A., 1982 April 23 (Folder 6)
    - Gelfand, Alan
      - 1980
        - October 27 (Folder 7)
        - October 28 (Folder 8)
      - 1982 (Box 81)
        - March 24 (Folder 1)
        - April 2 (Folder 2)
        - April 21 (Folder 3)
    - Gibby, Rickey C., 1983 February 24 (Folder 4)
    - Glotzer, Albert, 26. Notes only, 1982 March (Folder 5)
    - Heisler, Edward Thomas, 1980
      - December 2 (Folder 6)
      - December 3 (Folder 7)
      - Corrections to depositions (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Exhibits to depositions (Folder 2)
    - Jenness, Douglas, 1982
      - March 30 (Folder 3)
      - April 1 (Folder 4)
    - Lewit, Morris, 1982 February 16 (Folder 5)
    - Marcus, Bruce, 1982 April 30 (Folder 6)
    - Morrow, Felix, 1982 (Box 83)
      - March 25 (Folder 1)
      - March 29 (Folder 2)
    - Novack, George, 1982
      - March 15 (Folder 3)
      - March 16 (Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, Vaughan T., 1982 March 31 (Folder 5)
    - Parisi, Vincent, 1983 February 24 (Folder 6)
    - Sale, Louis J. (as custodian of records), 3. Notes only, 1982 November (Folder 7)
    - Seigle, Larry, 1982 (Box 84)
      - March 17 (Folder 1)
      - March 18 (Folder 2)
      - March 19 (Folder 3)
    - Van Heijenoort, Jean, 26. Notes only, 1982 April (Folder 4)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice, 1982 November 11 (Folder 5)
    - Weissman, George L., 1982 April 29 (Folder 6)
    - Zborowski, Mark, 1982 April 15 (Folder 7)
  - Hearing transcripts, 1980-1989 (Box 85)
    - General
      - List and notes (Folder 1)
      - Docket sheets (Folder 2)
      - Civil minutes (Folder 3)
    - 1980 December 1 (Folder 4)
    - 1981
      - July 27 (Folder 5)
      - December 7 (Folder 6)
    - 1982
      - February 1 (Folder 7)
      - February 3 (Folder 8)
      - March 3 (Folder 9)
      - (Judge Pfaelzer), March 22 (Folder 10)
      - (Judge Tassopulos), March 22 (Folder 11)
      - April 6 (Folder 12)
      - (Judge Pfaelzer), April 19 (Folder 13)
      - (Judge Tassopulos), April 19 (Folder 14)
      - May 10 (Folder 15)
      - July 12 (Folder 16)
      - August 12 (Folder 17)
      - October 18 (Folder 18)
      - November 8 (Folder 19)
    - 1983
      - January 4 (Folder 20)
      - January 19 (Folder 21)
      - January 31 (Folder 22)
      - February 7 (Folder 23)
      - March 21 (Folder 24)
      - July 15 (Folder 25)
    - 1987 June 1 (Folder 26)
    - 1989 November 13 (Folder 27)
  - Chronological file of official court documents, Motions, petitions, briefs, stipulations, affidavits, proposed findings, memoranda of law, notices, orders, applications, requests, interrogatories, statements, declarations, responses, reports, and exhibits to the above, 1979-1989 (Box 86)
    - 1979
      - July. Plaintiff's complaint for civil rights violations (Folder 1)
      - September. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion to dismiss (Folder 2-3)
      - October. Includes federal defendants' motion to dismiss (Folder 4-6)
      - November (Folder 7-9)
    - 1980
      - June (Folder 10)
      - July (Folder 11-12)
      - August (Folder 13)
      - September. Includes federal defendants' answer to amended complaint, and Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion for summary judgment (Folder 14-19)
      - October (Folder 20-21)
      - November. Includes plaintiff's statement of genuine issues, plaintiff's interrogatories, and Socialist Workers Party defendants' answer to amended complaint (Box 87, Folder 1-8)
      - December (Folder 9)
    - 1981
      - January (Folder 10)
      - May (Folder 11-15)
      - June (Folder 16-17)
      - July (Folder 18-19)
      - August. Includes federal defendants' responses to interrogatories (Folder 20-21)
      - September. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' responses to interrogatories (Box 88, Folder 1-3)
      - October (Folder 4)
      - November. Includes federal defendants' responses to interrogatories and motion to dismiss, and Socialist Workers Party defendants' answer to amended complaint (Folder 5-10)
      - December. Includes plaintiff's motion to compel discovery from Socialist Workers Party defendants (Folder 11-15)
    - 1982
      - January. Includes plaintiff's motion to compel discovery from federal defendants (Folder 16-19)
      - February. Includes plaintiff's interrogatories (Folder 20-24)
      - March. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion for protective order, and responses to interrogatories, and plaintiff's motion for protective order (Box 89, Folder 1-13)
      - April. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion to compel deposition answers from plaintiff, and federal defendants' responses to interrogatories (Folder 14-27)
      - May (Folder 28-36)
      - June. Includes plaintiff's statement of genuine issues (Box 90, Folder 1-5)
      - July. Includes court orders prohibiting publication of depositions (Folder 6-11)
      - August. Includes plaintiff's emergency petition for writ of mandamus (Folder 12-17)
      - September. Includes plaintiff's motion for additional pretrial discovery (Box 91, Folder 1-3)
      - October (Folder 4-12)
      - 17. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion for protective order, November 2- (Folder 13-17)
      - 30. Includes plaintiff's motions to compel production of documents and depositions from Los Angeles Police Department and from Mark Zborowski, November 22- (Box 92, Folder 1-4)
      - 29. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion to compel production of documents from Los Angeles Police Department, and interrogatories, and plaintiff's motion for production of Sylvia Doxsee grand jury transcripts, December 1- (Folder 5-20)
      - December 29 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - 1983
      - 15. Includes plaintiff's pretrial memorandum of contentions of fact and law, Socialist Workers Party defendants' pretrial memorandum of contentions of fact and law, and emergency petition for writ of mandamus, and federal defendants' memorandum of contentions of fact and law, January 3- (Folder 2-10)
      - 28. Includes plaintiff's interrogatories and responses to interrogatories, and Socialist Workers Party defendants' interrogatories and motions to dismiss for lack of subject matter jurisdiction and for stay of all further proceedings, January 17- (Box 94, Folder 1-17)
      - 12. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion that Judge Pfaelzer disqualify herself, February 1- (Folder 18-25)
      - 28. Includes plaintiff's trial brief and responses to interrogatories, and Socialist Workers Party defendants' answer to interrogatories, February 14- (Box 95, Folder 1-11)
      - March. Includes Sylvia Doxsee grand jury testimony released to plaintiff (Folder 12-15)
      - April (Folder 16-17)
      - May (Folder 18-19)
      - July (Folder 20-21)
      - August. Includes plaintiff's interrogatories re attorneys' fees and costs (Folder 22-23)
      - September. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' responses to interrogatories (Folder 24-29)
      - October (Box 96, Folder 1-13)
      - November (Folder 14)
    - 1984
      - April (Folder 15)
      - May (Folder 16)
      - June (Folder 17)
      - July (Folder 18)
    - 1985 February (Folder 19)
    - 1986
      - January (Folder 20)
      - February (Folder 21)
    - 1987
      - February. Includes Socialist Workers Party defendants' motion for interim award of attorney's fees and costs (Folder 22)
      - March (Folder 23)
      - April (Folder 24-28)
      - May (Box 97, Folder 1-3)
      - June (Folder 4)
    - Socialist Workers Party defendants' request for decision on motion for fees and costs without further delay, 1988 April (Folder 5)
    - 1989
      - August. Judge Pfaelzer's findings of fact and conclusions of law (Folder 6)
      - September (Folder 7-10)
      - October (Folder 11-14)
      - November (Folder 15)
  - Legal correspondence, 1979-1990
    - 1979-1980 (Folder 16)
    - 1981
      - January-October (Folder 17)
      - November (Folder 18)
      - December (Folder 19)
    - 1982
      - January-May (Folder 20)
      - June-September (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - October-December (Folder 2)
    - 1983
      - January (Folder 3)
      - February-December (Folder 4)
    - 1984 (Folder 5)
    - 1985-1986 (Folder 6)
    - 1987 (Folder 7)
    - 1988
      - March (Folder 8)
      - April (Folder 9)
      - May-November (Folder 10)
    - 1989-1990 (Folder 11)
  - Bills, 1981-1988 (Folder 12)
  - Background material (Box 99)
    - Chronologies of case, 1979-1983 (Folder 1)
    - Gelfand (Alan) expulsion file. Correspondence between Gelfand and party leaders, and records of internal proceedings, 1977-1979 (Folder 2)
    - Internal reports, Includes reports on Workers League and Workers Revolutionary Party as well as on legal case, 1971-1990 (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - Workers League/Workers Revolutionary Party, 1973-1981 (Folder 4)
      - Letters of support, 1976
        - A-D (Folder 5)
        - F-K (Folder 6)
        - L-S (Folder 7)
        - T-Z (Folder 8)
      - Letters of support, 1983
        - A-G (Folder 9)
        - H-M (Folder 10)
        - N-Y (Folder 11)
      - General (Box 100)
        - 1975 (Folder 1)
        - 1976 (Folder 2)
        - 1977 (Folder 3)
        - 1978-1979 (Folder 4)
        - 1980-1989 (Folder 5)
    - Publicity material. Leaflets, press releases, and news stories, 1976-1989 (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter. Clippings and articles (not from Socialist Workers Party press or Workers League/Workers Revolutionary Party press), 1976-1986 (Folder 7)
    - Socialist Workers Party and related typescripts of speeches and articles
      - Gordon, Sam, "Healy's Smear against Trotsky's Last Collaborators,", 1976 (Folder 8)
      - Novack, George, "Speech against the Falsifiers,", 1976 (Folder 9)
      - Camejo, Peter, and Fred Murphy, "Warning to Supporters of Nicaraguan Revolution,", 1980 (Folder 10)
    - Socialist Workers Party and related publications
      - Vithana, Jaya, Ceylon and the Healy School of Falsification, 1973 (Folder 11)
      - Marxism vs. Ultraleftism: The Record of Healy's Break with Trotskyism, 1974 (Folder 12)
      - Healy's Big Lie: The Slander Campaign against Joseph Hansen, George Novack, and the Fourth International, 1976 (Folder 13)
      - Newspaper and journal articles
        - 1964-1968 (Folder 14)
        - 1975 (Folder 15)
        - 1976 (Folder 16)
        - 1977 (Folder 17)
        - 1983-1984 (Folder 18)
    - Workers League/Workers Revolutionary Party and related publications
      - Security and the Fourth International: An Inquiry into the Assassination of Leon Trotsky, 1975 (Folder 19)
      - Accomplices of the GPU, 1976 (Folder 20)
      - The Indictment Stands, 1976 (Folder 21)
      - Robins, Harold, Security at Coyoacan, 1977 (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - Sylvia Franklin Dossier, 1977 (Folder 2)
      - Trotsky's Assassin at Large, 1977 (Folder 3)
      - The Life and Death of Tom Henehan: Martyr of the Fourth International, Also includes second edition, 1980, 1978 (Folder 4)
      - Manifesto: 40th Anniversary of the Fourth International, 1978 (Folder 5)
      - Cuidado con la Conspiración de la CIA y del SWP en contra de la Revolución Nicaragüense, 1979 (Folder 6)
      - The Case for a Labor Party, 1980 (Folder 7)